# **Alice Zhang**

User Experience Designer with 7 years of experience in SaaS for B2B environments specializing in visual design, accessibility, and UX strategy. Specializing in transforming ambiguity into clear, user-centred solutions, with a focus on creating memorable experiences.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **UI and UX Designer - Pelesys for CAE**

Richmond, Canada | January 2022-September 2024

- Designed Figma and Sketch mockups for the Learning Management System app redesign, collaborating with an international team of developers and product managers.
- Improved existing design of the fill-in-the-blanks question type, enhancing the exam creation process for course admins.
- Collaborated with CAE design team to create icon designs for a new design system used in all app rewrites.

## **UX Designer - Evident Point Software for PressReader**

Richmond, Canada | January 2019-November 2021

- Established project foundation for a 500K online school workbook initiative at PressReader's EdTech department; project green-lit after stakeholder presentation.
- Led competitive analysis of 14 products in user research, identifying improvement areas and presenting findings to stakeholders to inform product design.
- Updated client visual branding and print design, adjusting brand colors to meet WCAG AA contrast standards.

## **UX Designer & Developer - Plaid Consulting**

Vancouver, Canada | May 2018-July 2019

- Designed a web app prototype in Adobe XD and Proto.io, incorporating brand colors and typography; built with ReactJS, Bootstrap, SASS, NodeJS, and tracked with Git Bash.
- Conducted user research through interviews with data analysts and institutional researchers to define user needs for the web app.

#### Web Communications Assistant - DFO Canada

Vancouver, Canada | September 2015-April 2016

- Updated DFO government webpages to a new, accessible HTML/CSS and Bootstrap template.
- Designed monthly newsletters in Photoshop and InDesign.

## **EDUCATION**

## Simon Fraser University, Canada

BSc in Interactive Arts and Technology | 2020 Certificate in Computing Studies | 2020

## Malmö University, Sweden

Interaction Design BA Course in Full-time Exchange Program | 2017

- alice-zhang-portfolio.com
- alzh13579@gmail.com
- **L** +1 778 788 3568
- inkedin.com/in/alice-zhang
- alice\_slicez
- alice\_slicez

#### **DESIGN SKILLS**

Wireframing

User Interface Design

Visual Design

Print Design

## **UX METHODS**

User Experience Research

User Interviewing

**Competitor Product Analysis** 

**User Journey Mapping** 

Persona Creation

**Usability Testing** 

Accessibility Testing

## **TOOLS**

Figma

Sketch

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator,

InDesign, Lightroom

Miro, LucidChart

Notion

Airtable

## **CODING**

HTML

CSS/SASS

Javascript

Git Bash

#### LANGUAGE PROFICIENCIES

English

Mandarin Chinese